Srisanmathi Ramachandran

1025 Canyon Shadows Ct, Cary, NC 27519 | (984) 292-9166 | sramac13@uncc.edu https://www.linkedin.com/in/srisanmathi-ramachandran | https://srisanmathi.github.io/

SUMMARY

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - Creative minded professional with a keen interest in Software Development. Hands-on experience in application development using Java and JavaScript. Ability to quickly adapt to new technologies and excel in collaborating with peers.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

: Java 8, JavaScript (ES6), TypeScript, Python, SQL, HTML5 Languages

Frameworks : NodeJS (Express), ReactJS, Angular, CSS3, React Native, Spring Boot

Tools : Git, GitHub, Jira, Postman, Swagger, Selenium, Mocha, Junit, Linux, Docker, Kubernetes

: MySQL, MongoDB, FireStore **Databases**

Cloud Technologies: AWS(EC2, S3, RDS, Lambda, API Gateway), Google Cloud(Firebase), Azure, Digital Ocean, Heroku

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Computer Science

May 2020 University of North Carolina at Charlotte, Charlotte, NC GPA: 3.9/4.0 **Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science** May 2018 Kumaraguru College of Technology, Tamil Nadu, India GPA: 3.3/4.0

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Graduate Teaching Assistant

Jan 2020 - May 2020

University of North Carolina at Charlotte, NC

- Assisted head faculty for the Database Systems (SQL, NoSQL, AWS) graduate course and involved in classroom teaching
- Increased class performance by encouraging active class participation and mentoring students

Software Developer Intern, Resolve

May 2019 - Aug 2019

Columbus, Ohio

- Worked on an Agile (Scrum) Development team to deliver regular updates to business team and project managers
- Developed a mobile application for Android and iOS platform using React Native framework
- Interacted with Firebase (Authentication, Cloud Fire Store, Cloud Functions, Cloud Storage) for backend functions
- Used Git for version control and Jira for project tracking

Graduate Research Assistant

Jan 2019 - May 2019

University of North Carolina at Charlotte, NC

- Worked on a research project using Wi-Fi sensing to identify humans based on body shape and movement patterns
 - Used Angular JS along with angular material library and visualized the status of networking components using d3.js

Software Engineering Intern, Astra Infosys

Mar 2018 - May 2018

Coimbatore, India

- Worked with a team of 5 members to develop and maintain Spring Boot enterprise Java applications
- Developed SQL queries, views, stored procedures, indexes, events and triggers to efficiently retrieve data
- Performed automation using Selenium Web Driver to conduct functional testing

RELEVANT ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Amazing Places Finder (Angular 8, NodeJS, MongoDB, Swagger, Microsoft Azure, Digital Ocean)

Feb 2020

- Developed a single page MVC application to display places of interest using Angular 8, NodeJS/ Express and MongoDB
- Performed Unit testing using Mocha, validated and authorized users using JWT tokens
- Used web search capabilities of Bing by fetching news articles about a place from Microsoft Azure News Search API
- Documented the code by creating Open API specification for the RESTful API using Swagger
- Deployed the application on Digital Ocean CentOS Linux droplet using Nginx and PM2

Cinemax Movie Portal Application (ReactJS, Spring MVC, Spring Boot, MySQL, Postman)

May 2020

- Created a web application using ReactJS and Spring Boot to store and display the list of popular movies
- Connected to MySQL database using Spring Data JPA and performed unit testing using Junit framework

Ticketing Tool (MySQL, MySQL Work Bench, NodeJS/Express, AWS RDS)

Dec 2018

- Implemented a ticketing tool for IT organizations to keep track of the tickets raised using MySQL relational database
- Refined user stories and designed conceptual and logical data models using ER and UML diagrams
- Implemented stored procedures, triggers, indices, events and transactions and generated RESTful APIs using NodeJS

City Explore Planner Application (Java, Android)

Nov 2019

- Developed a trip planner to add trips, add new places in the trips, delete places and to display a map of the trip
- Interacted with Google Places and Maps API to get list of suggested places and draw a path using Google Maps API